<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jack of All Data, Master of Some</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jack of All Data, Master of Some</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything for Every Occasion</title>
      <link>/post/everything-for-every-occasion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/everything-for-every-occasion/</guid>
      <description>Clustering of similar product items can help decision makers strategically plan product mixes which can affect overall business strategy. In this post, I go over how to group similar products together using data from an online events retailer.
The Technical GistDon’t “blindly” standardize/normalize features without thinking about what you are actually trying to convey with each feature. Sometimes it makes more sense to normalize row-wise.
If you value interpretability of clusters over all else, the features you engineer must make sense and come from hypotheses that you have formed from looking at the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello? Anyone There?</title>
      <link>/post/call-center-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/call-center-simulation/</guid>
      <description>This post will deal with how to approach a problem using simulation. Furthermore, some theory on the distribution of order statistics shall be touched on as well as some very basic Queueing Theory concepts.
ContextSay you are trying to reach an international number. It can cost a fortune to reach an operator on the other side of the world. You have limited funds and you wish to simulate a call centre system to estimate how likely you are to reach an operator before you run out of money.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>